hey everyone welcome back to our Channel
I am back with another interesting topic
in the tosa automation
playlist so continuing with our topic on
test automation obstacles let's look at
our next obstacle which is called the
meeting scheduler now this is another
Dynamic table or a stat I table which
has got some calendar like structure
with some timings and then the days and
then the status of uh the meeting room
whether it is available or not and out
of this uh we need to find a room on
Thursday uh 11 to13 is the timing and we
need to find whether it is open or
closed okay so basically this particular
status right so on Thursday we need to
find this particular timing and then we
need to find the status whether it is
open or closed and then we need to type
that particular status uh in this uh
text box so for me it is open right now
so if I type this then the obstacle is
completed okay so it seems to be a
pretty simple one uh considering we have
done some complex tables and uh this one
is pretty simple the reason why it is
simple is because uh it has already
provided us the row okay and also it has
provided us the column so the THS day
refers to the column header and the 11
to 13 timing is the row header so once
you know which row or which column you
have to work on then it becomes a little
easier now in some other scenario this
could be more interesting or a little
difficult when you don't know the timing
okay so in this case it is fixed but
think that um it is a dynamic timing so
you need to find the status of that
particular timing and it keeps on
changing then it becomes a little
interesting but for us uh in this
particular case it is static so we'll go
ahead and automate this uh in tosa so
coming back to tosa the first step is
again to scan this particular module so
we'll go to our obstacles
and here we will scan this particular
application okay and I basically need uh
these two elements one is the time table
and the other is the result text which
is a text box okay and then I'm going to
rename the module with this obstacle
number
and then I'm going to save this and
close this
okay now uh going back to tosa again uh
going back to test cases section and
obstacles we'll be creating a new
obstacle test
case and then uh we are going to add the
module to this particular test case
Okay okay so we have got the table and
the text
now what we need to do here is pretty
simple so we need to select the row and
the row here is this right so 11 to13 is
the text which is present in this
particular row right so we can take that
text directly and tosa will be able to
select it with this particular text
right so we'll go back here and in the
row we will put this particular
text okay so it will uh select the the
row based on this particular text if it
is unique if it is not unique then um we
need to make some more adjustments but
right now it is unique okay and then in
the cell uh we can check that these are
all the column headers which are
displaying here so we need to select
Thursday
here and uh then instead of verify we
will do a buffer okay and uh in this I
will say
bore status
so it will be stored uh in this
particular buffer name which is bore
status and then in the result text I can
just use the buffer okay so this time
around I will use the send
keys and inside this I will use the
buffer okay so bcore
status so this is all we need to do in
this particular test case um and now
let's change the obstacle to complet it
and then uh let's try and execute this
and let's see whether it is able to grab
the status and enter it into the
particular text box right so run this in
scratchbook okay so as you can see it
was able to grab the status based on the
row name and then uh based on the column
it picked up status which is present in
that particular cell okay and then it
entered it into the text box which
completed the obstacle so a pretty
simple obstacle you just need to know
how to steer the web tables based on
different row heading or the column
heading or you can use different types
of action modes based on your specific
scenario that's all for this particular
video if you have any questions then
please leave it in the comments
if you like this video then please
subscribe to our Channel thanks for
watching and I will see you in the next
video